const STORE = {
  questions: [
    //1
    {
      question: "How many US Presidents were slave owners?",
      options: ["12", "8", "3", "13"],
      answer: "12",
      explanation:
        "Washington, Jefferson, Madison, Monroe, Jackson, VanBuren, Polk, Tyler, A. Johnson, Grant, Harrison, and Taylor",
    },
    //2
    {
      question:
        "When were slaves first brought to the English colonies in North America?",
      options: ["1582", "1490", "1619", "1750"],
      answer: "1619",
      explanation: "in Jamestown Virgina",
    },
    //3
    {
      question:
        "The 1860 US Census estimated there were this many enslaved people that year?",
      options: ["3 million", "4 million", "6 million", "8 million"],
      answer: "4 million",
      explanation: "an estimated 14% of the US population",
    },
    //4
    {
      question: "When did African-American men first have the right to vote?",
      options: ["1865", "1900", "1870", "1920"],
      answer: "1870",
      explanation: "the 15th Amendment",
    },
    //5
    {
      question: "When did African-American women first have the right to vote?",
      options: ["1965", "1920", "1890", "1900"],
      answer: "1965",
      explanation:
        "with the Voting Rights Act signed by President Lyndon Johnson",
    },
    //6
    {
      question: "When did white women first have the right to vote?",
      options: ["1965", "1920", "1860", "1900"],
      answer: "1920",
      explanation: "the 19th Amendement",
    },
    //7
    {
      question: "How many years was the Confederate United States a country?",
      options: ["6", "9", "2", "4"],
      answer: "4",
      explanation: "1861-1865, the same years as the American Civil War",
    },
    //8
    {
      question: "When was the first African-American elected to US Congress?",
      options: ["1930", "1870", "1890", "1900"],
      answer: "1870",
      explanation:
        "two men were elected to serve in Congress, Senator Hiram Revels of Mississippi, and Representative Joseph Rainey of South Carolina",
    },
    //9
    {
      question: "How many members of US Congress are African-American in 2020?",
      options: ["27", "93", "58", "114"],
      answer: "58",
      explanation: "2 Senators and 56 Representatives",
    },
    //10
    {
      question:
        "Who was the first woman to run for the President of the United States?",
      options: [
        "Hilary Clinton",
        "Shirley Chislom",
        "Geraldiine Farraro",
        "Carole Mosley Braun",
      ],
      answer: "Shirley Chislom",
      explanation:
        "in 1972, she was the first African-American woman elected to the US Congress in 1968",
    },
  ],
  questionNumber: 0,
  score: 0,
};
